<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Pranav Rajan&#39;s Blog</title>
<link>https://mozartfish.github.io/blog/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://mozartfish.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>This is a blog</description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>FastAI Lecture 0: How to FastAI</title>
  <dc:creator>Pranav Rajan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://mozartfish.github.io/blog/posts/fastai-lecture0/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I’ve recently started <a href="https://course.fast.ai/">FastAI Practical Deep Learning for Coders</a> to learn about machine learning. To hold myself accountable and finish the course I am going to try to write a blog post for every video in the series starting with <code>Lecture 0</code>. By doing this my goal is to not only learn about deep learning and track my progress but reinforce my learning by trying to explain what I’ve learned for people new to machine learning like me. <code>Lecture 0</code> isn’t officially presented in the course until <code>Lecture 3</code> but it provides valuable advice for how to complete FastAI and actually learn how to write deep learning code.</p>
<p><code>Lecture 0</code> doesn’t have any code examples or notebooks but I took Jeremy’s advice about blogging and interacting with the community by setting up this Quarto blog as the <code>Lecture 0</code> project. <code>Lecture 0</code> was created in 2020 before Twitter became X and closed off to people who didn’t have an account. Since then, some of the ML community and other academic communities in CS have migrated to <code>Discord</code> , <code>Mastodon</code>, and <code>Bluesky</code>. I’d recommend checking out the <code>FastAI Forums</code> and <code>FastAI Discord</code> since there’s an active community and study groups specifically for this course.</p>
<section id="jeremy-howards-advice" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="jeremy-howards-advice">Jeremy Howard’s Advice</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Commit to finish the course</li>
<li>Try to finish one really good project to show off what you’ve learned in the course</li>
<li>Share and blog about your work</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="how-to-watch-a-fastai-lesson" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="how-to-watch-a-fastai-lesson">How to Watch A FastAI Lesson</h2>
<p>This advice was presented by Jeremy in <code>Lecture 0</code></p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Watch FastAI Lecture</p></li>
<li><p>Run notebooks and code presented in the lecture and experiment with code</p></li>
<li><p>Reproduce notebook from a clean notebook (Jeremy provides clean notebooks on github)</p></li>
<li><p>Repeat with a different dataset (could be personal project)</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="resources" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="resources">Resources</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gGxe2mN3kAg">FastAI Lecture 0: How to FastAI</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://christinemcleavey.com/learning-about-deep-learning/">Christine Mcleavey’s Blog</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://quarto.org/">Quarto</a></p></li>
</ol>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>learning</category>
  <category>fastai</category>
  <category>deep learning</category>
  <guid>https://mozartfish.github.io/blog/posts/fastai-lecture0/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Welcome To My Blog</title>
  <dc:creator>Pranav Rajan</dc:creator>
  <link>https://mozartfish.github.io/blog/posts/welcome/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>This is my first blog post. Welcome!</p>
<p>I decided to start a blog inspired by Jeremy Howard’s Lecture 0 from the FastAI Course. Jeremy and FastAI used to maintain a blogging and publication tool called FastPages but transitioned to a new publication system called Quarto.</p>
<p>This blog is written in Quarto. Why Quarto? In the past I had attempted to used Medium and Substack but never fully spent the time to learn the tools to write a blog post. I decided to learn and publish with Quarto because of its capabilities to produce high quality scientific and technical documents with the ability to embed code and visualizations for review. Another reason why I like Quarto is how easy it is to write markdown and publish a blog.</p>
<p>Going forward I hope to use Quarto to write about my programming projects, thoughts,and improve my writing.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>news</category>
  <guid>https://mozartfish.github.io/blog/posts/welcome/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://mozartfish.github.io/blog/posts/welcome/thumbnail.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
